

# Errell Niño

mobile: +63 908 889 3730 errellnino@gmail.com Skype ID: errell.nino



https://ph.linkedin.com/in/errellhttp://be.net/errellhttps://goo.gl/dXzPqe

UX Creative Professional; Design Sprint Facilitator Product Development & Customer Experience

#### Highlights

The demand of an ever-increasing frequency of change on every media, challenges me to produce the highest possible design for any business and target audiences using straight-forward, minimal, crisp, flexible and adaptable creative design solutions, which is second to none.

Been in the graphic & design scene since 1996 in a team, specialising in creative graphic/visual design in web, print, video and mobile. Able to work in administering, directing, training, installing and maintaining the company's brand using different graphic design and marketing tools.

Worked and collaborated with America Online (AOL) Member Services, Cyber City Teleservices, NexC, Magnus Philippines, PFSWeb-ECOST, ArtAsia-UNICEF, and Asian Hospital and Medical Center, including government institutions namely, Department of Health (DOH), Department of Tourism (DOT), Department of Energy (DOE), National Power Corporation (NAPOCOR), and National Telecommunications Commission (NTC).

As a creative design lead, I always create inspiring, strategic, and innovative ideas for clients that work in a fully integrated manner, both online and offline. It's very much a people-oriented job, involving development of high-level concepts for visual design projects. It also involves working with internal and external clients, pitching designs, and understanding client needs. Also responsible for recruiting designers as well as internal design resources.

#### Experience

2/2018 – Present - 2/2017 - 2/2018 - Senior Lead UX | UI 2/2017 - 2/2018 - UX | UI Lead

**Stratpoint Technologies Inc, Digital Enterprise Software Solutions** 

Digital Enterprise Software Solutions company with over 20 years of experience in developing software for the enterprise and consumer markets globally. A Digital Transformation enabler, fluent in the languages of digital technology.

My responsibilities are as follows:

- Leads HCD team creative sessions for project kick-offs.
- Establishes creative direction for the entire line of online-offline services and programs.
- Develops creative programs and design concepts that meet the business objectives of the organisation and that advance brand strategies.
- · Supervises, inspire, mentor, and coach the UXUI team; generates multiple concepts for a projects and
- products.
- Works with internal teams to generate ideas for pitching and proposals.
- Provide quality control over concepts and projects.
- Knowledge and thirst to investigate, innovate, and develop trends in creative with an emphasis on enterprise portals through web and mobile applications.
- Design explorations for User Interfaces, User Experiences, and related visual design.

### 6/2009 – 2/2015 | Creative Design Lead (UX/UI) / Creative Director **TwistResources Inc.**

TwistResources specialise in high-performance sites and applications optimised for web or mobile. Creative through to complex logic; projects large or small, we pride ourselves on being serious people for serious organisations. It takes advantage of the ToolTwist framework that eases development of web and mobile web applications allowing the team to deliver at a shorter time possible.

### 11/2008 – 3/2009 | Senior Web Designer **PFSWeb - eCost**

PFSweb, Inc. (Priority Fulfillment Services) is an international provider of eCommerce solutions. Main role accountabilities are as follow: Creates campaigns for marketing collaterals i.e newsletters, email catalogs, ebrochures, etc.; Creates product comps for various offers on ecost.com production sites; Mentors junior graphic designers; Monitors newsletter, email catalogs, etc. styles and product images releases; Regular backups of image repositories; Attends weekly meetings with the Marketing Director, Product Owners, etc.; Maintains over-all style of the ecost brand across the company.

### 9/2001 – 7/2008 | Creative Consultant / Creative Director iCanvasMedia

iCanvasMedia is a design and photography publishing house. It caters mostly government and private clients accounts. Main responsibilities are: Conceptual layout and design of various printed materials (i.e. magazines, annual reports, special edition prints, books, etc.); Collaborated directly to the Editor-in-Chief on every projects; Send proofs and feedbacks, suggestions on the over-all design and layout; Manages photoshoots of executive profiles of the company; Directly collaborates with the corporte communications for clients requirements; Pre-press production when needed.

## 8/2001 –10/2001 | Senior Consultant for Web Design - Project Based **Magnus Asia Philippines**

Magnus Asia is an independent consultancy firm that specialises in the design and realisation of integral IT solutions through which companies are able to strengthen their competitive position and take on a leading role in their value chain.

### 1/2001 – 8/2001 | Senior Web Designer **NexC**

NexC is the one-stop solution to all the needs of hospitality industry professionals worldwide. It is one of the largest information sources with active users in over 200 countries. Backed by a talented and experienced international team and with the active participation of all its members, NexC today continues to search for new ways to enhance its services and create new and innovative ideas that will keep our industry in the forefront of modern management.

### 7/1999 – 1/2001 | Senior Web Designer (Pioneering Core Team) **Cyber City Teleservices, Ltd**

Cyber City Teleservices, Ltd. provides call center outsourcing solutions. It offers BPO services, including data entry, data processing, data mining, data cleansing, form processing, document digitalisation, legal transcription, fulfillment and payment processing, sales order management, and point of sale transaction management. It also provides call center; customer; call center collection; DRTV offshore call center support; and technical support services.

### 09/1997 – 06/1999 | TechMail Consultant **AOL Member Services Philippines, Inc.**

AOL Member Services Philippines, a giant U.S. online service provider, which offers a range of integrated products and properties including communication tools, mobile services and subscription packages which drive traffic across the AOL network. Key role responsibilities includes: Works closely with customers to help their technical issues on AOL products; Offers help in all project stages from troubleshooting to answering day-to-day questions via email correspondence; Finds solutions to customer's day-to-day issues under time pressure; and Provides technical product training to non-technical colleagues.

#### **Education / Certifications**

1992 – 1996 | Angeles University Foundation | Angeles City, Philippines Bachelor's Degree in Nursing | PRC Registered Nurse - Renal/Haemodialysis

INS Certified Intravenous Therapy Nurse (IVTN)

Certified Design Sprint Facilitator / Certified Product Development Innovator DLSU Graduate School of Business - SixSigma PH [License ICPDCE-2018-0925-0002]

Google Analytics Individual Qualification [License 29246691]

Google Creative Certification Exam [License 29132201]

Able to speak basic Arabic; Studies in German Language

#### Skills

Agile / Scrum

Design Thinking / Design Sprint

UX and UI Design

Usability, Usertest, and Research

Visual Design

Design Systems / Design Ops

Service Design

Wireframing & Prototyping

Research and Usability

Motion Graphics / Videography

Photography

Pre-Press / Offset Printing

Branding & Identity

Typography

HTML / CSS / Responsive Design

SEO, Google Analytics, Digital Marketing

**Adobe Creative Cloud** 

#### Industries Serviced

FinTech / Banking • Ecommerce • Brands & Advertising • Education • Healthcare • Telecoms •

Technology • Retail • Gaming • Marketing • Media • Professional Networking • Social Networks • Government